nl.edu 2013-06-24

# LEGAL PAGES - PRIVACY POLICY - National Louis University

### Commitment to Your Privacy

We respect and are committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our web site. For this reason, we have adopted this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy will inform you on how your personal information is processed and used by National Louis University. We make the promise that we will take the necessary steps to use your personal information only in ways that are compatible with this Privacy Policy. The following policies are only in effect for the web pages, online applications, forms and newsletters owned and operated by National Louis University. The following discloses our Privacy Policy.

### What Information We Collect and How It Is Used

Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol Address (IP Address). When a visitor requests a page or file from the NLU web site, our servers automatically recognize that visitor's domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about you other than the IP address from which you have accessed our site. We use this information to examine our traffic in web site analytics software applications. We do not collect and evaluate this information for specific individuals. Our servers do not automatically record the e-mail addresses of our web site visitors.

When a visitor accesses and completes our online Admissions Application form and online Request More Information form, this data is collected and transmitted securely across the internet and housed in our administrative database for processing. We will never share, sell, or rent individual personal information unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is only available to employees managing this information for purposes of contacting you or sending you emails based on your request for information or for processing online applications submitted via our web site.

National Louis University has multiple means of communication with students, faculty, staff, alumni, and friends. Certain communications are internal and cannot be opted out of, especially those concerning campus health and safety. All other communications from NLU will provide opt-out controls within each communication and users will have the ability to unsubscribe from emails directly within the message. Opt-out preferences will be processed immediately and will be effective no later than 10 days after submission.

### Other Information About Online Privacy

The National Louis University web site contains many hyperlinks to third party web sites. In most cases, these links will open new browser windows. National Louis University is not responsible for the content of the web sites these links follow nor is National Louis University responsible for the privacy practices of these web sites. National Louis University does not share individual personal information you provide NLU with these third party web sites to which the National Louis University web site links. Please reference the privacy policies of these web sites to determine their privacy practices.

Whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example through e-mail, web-based forms and applications as well as many additional ways – National Louis University collects this information on its computing systems. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.

### Consent to This Agreement

By visiting and using the National Louis University web site you agree and consent to the collection and use of information by National Louis University as specified above. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

### Additional Information and Questions

At any point during your visit with us, if you have any questions concerning your privacy, please feel free to contact the [NLU webmaster](mailto:webdev@nl.edu "Email Webmaster").
